passionate about the gospel from from
the moment you found out in the moment
from the moment yeah so how did you
begin to study it how did you in three
months time you're saying that you knew
more than you could have imagined there
how did you did you have a system then
were you good well let me go back for a
second when you were in school were you
a good student you know I was a good
student and the thing is my I think my
passion like I remember we're gonna you
know growing up I wanted to be like into
psychology I liked how the human mind
works I was you know really like a
thinker I like to think about the way
people think and and how to dissect the
mind and that kind of thing you know
people's thoughts or whatever and so
that's where my passion was like really
growing up like yeah I think that's what
I'd like to do so I think there was
always a leading towards just that
creativity of the mind
mm-hm and as I said earlier when when I
was writing lyrics you know just it you
have to be poetical right so the way
that I would write my music you know
trying to find different ways creative
ways to get across a certain point when
I when it came to the Bible like I said
I didn't have a system I didn't know
that this is what I was doing because my
mind just worked that way mm-hmm so I
would read a text and something would
jump out to me that I would be like whoa
look at this like this but I didn't I
just thought it was uh normal like
everyone saw this you know so when I
start sharing some of this stuff with
like you know other people who were
Adventist they were like oh I never saw
that that way before and I look at them
like you never saw this this way before
what you know what do you mean mm-hmm
like yes kind of like right there don't
you see it no no I never saw that I
started studying using amazing fact
study guide
okay I actually wasn't study guys it was
Joe Cruz his little you know little
pamphlets that he wrote those little
pocket books and I would just get those
those little books and I would read and
I will highlight my Bible like my Bible
was like a coloring book and that's how
I kind of learned the basics as far as
doctrine a doctrine doctrine but like I
said I didn't realize that at that time
is only as I look back that I saw that I
was like I think the Lord called me in a
certain sense because I was coming from
the outside mm-hmm
because I had a mind that you know had
not been brought up in the church if you
will soul I was going to see things
differently yes just naturally yeah and
he would eventually lead me to develop
that into a system mhm mhm and so I
think you know as I look back that's how
I see this unfolding so it's not that I
came in and I was like okay I have a new
school of thought you know a new way of
studying the Bible that was just the way
that I approached the scripture and I
thought it was just normal
yeah but you had a what's been called a
tabula rasa the clean slate yeah you
came in without any preconceptions
really you know you just came in and
like Lord just show me yeah and he did
so I know people are probably saying why
aren't they talking about the system so
tell us how do you start if someone's
watching right now that's never studied
the Bible before where do you start do
you start in the New Testament you start
the Old Testament where do you start so
I'll share something practical right now
okay I one of the things that I use
right now when I study the Bible and
I've been using it for years is Bible
Software it's something called assort
so I don't know if you guys have ever
heard of Esau before it's a free
software now there are other software's
out there that you can purchase and
they're quite expensive some run like
thousands of dollars and so it's pretty
expensive a sword is pretty much free
I think you you know some places that
might cost like ten dollars or five
dollars or something like that but II
sort is a very powerful tool because it
basically brings the Bible you know to
your fingertips right you can have
different translations you can have
different commentaries dictionaries you
know you can look up a word in Greek in
Hebrew so that's a very it's a very
technical aspect of Bible study but it's
something that a lot of people really
don't know about you know back in the
day I'd study my Bible with a Bible and
a concordance the big thick book that's
all I had you know so I had my Bible my
concordance and it would take hours like
okay now what's this word or and you
know you're looking I'm trying to find a
word that is found in several different
places in the scriptures well now you
can do all that you know at the you know
just it's right there at your fingertips
yeah so on the technical side I'd say
get a good Bible Software again I use a
sword you can go to east sword - sword
dotnet and you can just download it
straight onto your computer so or
whatever software you you choose you
know get a good Bible software